# Ali Mobrem

(858)882-7483 Alimobrem@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/alimobrem

## **Director of Product Management**

Customer focused product manager with an extensive background in software development (CS Degree). 10+ years of experience throughout the product and software development lifecycle; designing, managing and leading teams to build products that solve real problems.

- Defined/Evangelized product roadmaps and value propositions to internal stakeholders, customers and prospects.
- Founding product manager for multiple offerings.
- Trusted advisor to senior leadership on Product Strategy/M&A.
- Coached and mentored junior product managers.
- Guided teams of architects, engineers, UI/UX, and doc writers.
- Drove execution based on SAFe, Agile and Scrum methodologies.
- Conducted design thinking workshops with teams spanning multiple BUs for cross BU initiatives.

# **Experience**

#### Product Management Director/CA Technologies, San Diego 2016-2018

Responsible for **driving strategy and execution** for CA's product portfolio used by Fortune 500 companies across Banking, Insurance, Manufacturing and Retail to automate and orchestrate critical business processes.

- Spearheaded the development of Intelligent Experience, a standardized UX platform with a UI Component Library, Cross-Product Communication, and Automated CI/CD Infrastructure; Offered customers a consistent UX experience across all key products to reduce development time to market by 20%.
- Led the product roadmap for Workload Automation and Analytics solutions, shipping developer-friendly REST APIs and a highly anticipated mobile web offering; Decreased customer backlog to lowest level in recent years and boosted NPS Score to beyond double the industry standard.
- Created an API driven self-service cloud business model on existing mission critical legacy software; Led a team of product managers and designers/architects, who collaborated with 10+ functional teams to build an initial offering with services including Service Catalog\Provisioning, Security\Identity Management, Developer Productivity, and API Management.
- Helped defined the product strategy for CA's Workload Automation (\$250M+ revenue) by developing requirements that ensured feature parity, competitive pricing and compelling product positioning; Led delivery of new solutions such as Agent Orchestration\Management, Cloud and Container Workloads, and Developer Enablement (APIs).
- Initiated an effort to become more customer-focused by sharing product requirements, roadmaps, design thinking practices, customer data, and market data across all functional teams; Resulted in increasing the realization rate to over 100%.

# Ali Mobrem

(858)882-7483 Alimobrem@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/alimobrem

## **Experience Cont.**

#### Product Management /CA Technologies, San Diego 2015-2016

- Helped manage CA Platform (PaaS) for the Office of the CTO, enabling product teams and developers at CA to build and launch enterprise SaaS solutions with speed and efficiency.
- Built services focused on authentication, monitoring, continuous integration and delivery, HA, and database administration, with multiple software teams locally and internationally.
- Shipped a container based micro-service architecture built on top of the RedHat OpenShift platform (Kubernetes, Docker) with CI/CD pipelines and a modern operations stack

#### Principal Software Engineer/CA Technologies, San Diego 2014-2015

 Enablement focused; On-boarded internals product teams to take advantage of the CA Platform (PaaS) by creating sample apps and libraries, and working hand in hand with developers to help port code/business logic from on-premise applications to new SaaS application running on the Platform.

#### Senior Software Engineer /CA Technologies, San Diego 2008-2014

- Contributed to the team that created the Platform UI components and services built using Ext JS, specifically created to help on-board products to the CA Platform (PaaS)
- Worked on projects spanning diverse technology areas such as server automation, data virtualization and UI development.

Software Engineer /CA Technologies, Santa Barbara 2003-2008 Associate Software Engineer /CA Technologies, Santa Barbara 2000-2003

## **Personal Projects**

**Hublix** – (2017–2018) SaaS based Marketing Automation Platform – <a href="https://hublix.com">https://hublix.com</a>
Focused on the product side and less on the development. Architected the product using a complete AWS stack that my team implemented. Built using AWS Serverless, Dynamo DB, API Gateway, SNS, etc.

PixINow – (2014–2016) Online Yearbook Creator\Editor – <a href="https://pixlnow.com">https://pixlnow.com</a>
Built an online yearbook creator/editor using the MEAN Stack. Self-taught vanilla JavaScript, jQuery, git/GitHub, CSS, angular, node, express, mongo, yeoman, grunt/gulp, CI/CD pipeline via shippable, open source libraries i.e FabricJS, etc. The initial version was built using Facebook's Parse platform. Subsequent redesigns utilized the MEAN stack deployed via Heroku and later deployed using docker on Digital Ocean.

## **Education**

Computer Science Degree (BS) / University of California, Santa Barbara

## **Awards\Certifications**

- San Diego Startup Weekend 1st Place & Crowd Favorite (Yo! Moments)
- LDP (Leadership Development Program) This year long program is designed to foster and cultivate the next generation of leaders.
- Pragmatic Marketing (PMC-VI) https://pragmaticmarketing.com/
- SAFe Agilest License 21717042-5448